<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Multi-Task Learning on Abdullah Al Mamun</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/multi-task-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multi-Task Learning on Abdullah Al Mamun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©newabdullah 2025</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/multi-task-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Evaluation of RecSys - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-evaluation-of-recsys-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-evaluation-of-recsys-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-why-this-post-matters-who-its-for-and-what-youll-learn&#34;&gt;Context: Why This Post Matters, Who It’s For, and What You’ll Learn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 3 of our four-part series on evaluating recommendation systems (RecSys)! In the previous installments, we laid the groundwork: Part 1 introduced foundational techniques like collaborative filtering (CF) and Matrix Factorization (MF), which excelled at capturing user-item interactions but assumed linearity, missing complex patterns. Part 2 explored Factorization Machines (FM) and XGBoost, which tackled sparse data and non-linear ranking but fell short on higher-order interactions and sequential behaviors. By 2016, these limitations spurred a seismic shift toward deep neural networks (DNNs), which transformed RecSys by learning intricate feature interactions, automating feature engineering, and addressing diverse tasks like sequential recommendations and multi-task optimization. This post traces that evolution from 2016 to 2023, diving into Neural Collaborative Filtering (NCF), Wide &amp;amp; Deep Learning, DeepFM, Deep Interest Network (DIN), Deep Learning Recommendation Model (DLRM), and Adaptive Task-to-Task Fusion (AdaTT). It’s tailored for data scientists, ML engineers, and tech professionals—particularly those designing large-scale RecSys in domains like e-commerce, streaming, and advertising—who need a deep, technical understanding of these advancements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
